# PRASHANT PRADEEP DHUMAL Featured

Highly qualified Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Application Programming, DevOps,Docker,Kubernetes Python,NodeJS,Linux,Unix, and also exposure to Embedded Systems.In dire need of job due to financial difficulties.



Current Designation: Technical Associate Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Communications Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Integrated VLSI and

Embedded System Design]

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineering, Python Programming, Devops, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Ubuntu, GIT, JIRA, Node. Js,

MongoDB, NoSQL, Embedded Systems, Data Recovery, Installation, Motherboard, Windows, Ubuntu

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

## **Summary**

Result-oriented Software Engineering Professional with 2.9 years of experience in Python Programming, Artificial Intelligence, DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, Node JS, Linux. Software Development.

A Post Graduate Diploma Holder from CDAC in the field Of Embedded Systems And VLSI Design , which enhanced the interest into software Engineering Field and the Operating Systems Like Windows, Linux, Embedded Systems, RTOS and the other trends providing deep insights into the Software Field

My professional and career objective is:

To work in an organization as a Software Engineerwhere my skills will be beneficial for the organization with which i will be working with for the benefit of Organization.

Total of 2.9 years of Multi domain experience in the field of Python, NodeJs, Mongodb, Linux, Windows and other tools like Git, JiRA and others.

Experience in the DevOps tools like Docker, Kubernetes which provide a good exposure to the upcoming Microservices and Containerisation platforms.

## **Work Experience**

Tata Communications as Technical Associate

Mar 2020 to Till Date

Worked as a Technical Associate in Tata Communications Pune.

**TATA COMMUNICATIONS LIMITED** as Technical Associate -Software Development Mar 2020 to Jul 2020

Responsibilities:

Involved in the Tata Communications leading SIM Management Technology known as MOVE which is related with the Mobility. Worked on the Service Delivery Process of TATA Communications involving innovation and the end-to-end SIM Delivery Process for the SIM CONNECT and IOT Connect custo

## RoxAl Pvt Ltd., as Software Engineer

Jul 2017 to Nov 2019

Technologies: Python, NodeJS, MongoDB, Machine Learning, Chatbot Development, Artificial Intelligence, DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, Operating Systems, Linux

#### Projects:

1. Automatic Calling System (July 2017 - October -2017) RoxAl Pvt. Ltd, Internship

Developed a prototype for already filled excel sheet and pick the phone number one by one from excel sheet. Using python. Automatic call processing to the number from the excel Sheet using GSM mobile and AT Commands

#### 2 . RoxBot (October 2017-June 2018)

RoxAl Pvt. Ltd. Full Time(Pvthon, NLP, Machine Learning)

Developed gliksense bot using NLP and gliksense data an appropriate format through api. Development of natural language processing using NLTK and other allied libraries using python

Used tensorflow Deep learning algorithm for qliksense user define questions for measures. Developed different channel like Telegram, Skype, Slack integration to the RoxBot. Involved in the deployment, hosting, testing of the Bot developed into the server in windows as as Ubuntu.

#### 3 .License Management System (July 2018 - October 2018)

RoxAl Pvt. Ltd, Full Time (MongoDB, NodeJS)

Developed License Management System using NodeJS and MongoDB to generate licenses for the QlikSense.

Developed API for CRUD operations and used various crypto libraries to make it secure.

#### 4. Ping Robotic Process Automation (Micro-Service for P i n g Alerting)

(February 2019 - July 2019 ) RoxAI, Full Time

Developed a code for transferring triggered alert to defined recipe like setting event in google outlook calendar, c r e a t i n g case on Jira or salesforce, send message to bot.

Encryption System Mechanism to interact with the teams (Android, iOS and Angular) with the help of cross platform tools. Implementation of the load balancing (nginx) servers for smooth processing of the operations Implementation of the services in Ubuntu Servers to ensure continuous smooth working of the applications.

5. Deployment using Docker and Kubernetes(July 2019 - November 2019)

Using Docker and the Kubernetes, implemented the deployer for the Ping where in the previous architecture was converted into Microservices where I was involved in the deployment phase using Docker. and the Kubernetes using tools like:docker-compose,Dockerfiles and Kompose for the deployments.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from University Of Pune in 2014

PG: PG Diploma (Integrated VLSI and Embedded System Design) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC) in 2015

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Python	
DOCKER	
Kubernetes	
nodeJS	
Linux	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=c5cb93895b73172e08bc27104f725ccb59540050491b5f450243135e08...

Hindi	Expert
Marathi	Proficient

## **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time